Gopi Macha

Software Engineer Intern

Phone Number (470) 659-9854 Email gmacha@students.kennesaw.edu Address Marietta, GA 30067

I have 2 years of experience and am a proficient in JavaScript, React JS, Angular JS, Jenkins, and Azure. Looking for a challenging Software Engineer role in your organization to put my abilities to good use. Having the ability to create software, analyze data, and troubleshoot complex technological problems. Good at putting together technical specifications that outline the architecture for new software and how it will be connected. Able to work well with others across departments to find new ways to solve problems and improve products' features and functionality. Considered a great performer and a powerful communicator. Webpage for the Kennesaw State University KISO association was successfully handled.

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gopi-macha-09b45a152/ Website: https://gopimacha.azurewebsites.net

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern

Honeywell Connected Enterprise, Atlanta, GA

May 2022 - Present

- Participated in ongoing training to enhance own job skills and knowledge.
- Developed the Cloud Cost Management Application and do additional Azure Analysis for most of the time as part of 2-interns team
- effectively used proprietary data formats, such JSON, to maintain the HONEYWELL project standards are followed.
- Wrote code to switch the React boilerplate from Mobx and Mobx Router to Redux and React-Router
- Made non-technical operation and workflow documentation in CONFLUENCE to help the non-coding team and a different person who might work on the cost-optimization project.
- I used Redux, which stores global state and actions that can be dispatched, and React Hooks, which takes care of state management on a per-component basis.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Kennesaw State University

Aug 2021 - May 2022

- Plan homework and provide students with clearly defined course objectives by conducting meetings and office hours discussions
- Serve as an approachable teaching assistant, enhancing learning via real-time laboratory experience or effective discussion sessions
- Professionally assist a faculty instructor in handling classes with greater strengths.
- Evaluated and grade examinations, assignments and papers and record grades.

Junior Application Developer | Web Developer

Enterpi Software Solution Private Limited

Dec 2018 - Jun 2020

- Collaborated with UI / UX designer to help create and implement best design practices
- Extensive knowledge of Angular JS methods for providing performant visual effects
- Efficiently created user stories by incorporating Azure DevOps Board and Trello
- Proved incredibly consistent by following an Agile & Scrum Methodology throughout the project roadmap

- Used HTML and CSS Bootstrap in the development in the front end of the application
- Major Projects: SCOREBIRD, ONCRAZE
- Responded quickly to meet customer needs and resolve problems.
- Analyzed user needs and software requirements to determine feasibility of design within time and cost constraints.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Software Engineering Candidate

GPA 4.0

Expected graduation Dec 2022

Kennesaw State University, MARIETTA, GA

Relevant Coursework

- Emerging Software Engineering Processes
- Software Architecture
- Web Service Engineering

- Cloud Computing
- Requirements Engineering

Awards & Honors

Member of Deans 4.0 list

Extracurricular Activities

Efficiently managed the website of the KISO group at Kennesaw State University.

Bachelor of Engineering In Computer Science and Engineering

GPA 3.3

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Hyderabad, Hyderabad, Telangana

Jun 2018

Relevant Coursework

- Data Structures
- Web Technologies
- Software Project Management

- Design and Analysis of Algorithms
- Software Engineering
- Object-Oriented Analysis and Design

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- JS Frameworks: React, Angular
- Software Documentation Control
- Software Design
- Agile Project Management
- Software Testing and Validation
- Typescript
- Jenkins
- Postman

- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Debugging and Troubleshooting
- Infrastructure Deployment
- NoSQL Databases
- Software Deployment
- JavaScript
- Eagerness to Learn New Technologies
- CSS Flexbox, Bootstrap

CERTIFICATIONS

AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals